Kevin M. Pratt

4210 Orion Rd, Rochester Hills, MI 48306 prattkev@gmail.com (248) 495-5950

Summary

High performing technologist excelling in several roles of the with extensive experience in the SDLC while consistently exceeding expectations for each role. Extensive work as a Product Owner in Data Analytics and Compliance software development, with focus on Data Privacy rights. Acting Product Manager for communication compliance products at Rocket Mortgage during restructure and expansion of program. Software development leader that optimized compliance marketing opportunities while maintaining highest level of compliance at Rocket Mortgage.

Education

- 2012-2014 Masters in Business Administration, Finance Concentration (Oakland University)
- 2006-2009 Bachelors of Science in Zoology and Pre-Veterinary Medicine (Michigan State)

Work Experience

2015 - 2023 - Rocket Mortgage/Central (Formerly Quicken Loans)

Technology Team Lead – **2.8 years.** Leader of an Agile/SAFE software development team at Rocket Mortgage the largest mortgage lender in the nation, ensuring compliance for all marketing and informational calls (over 1 million calls and texts/day). Headed up expansion of TCPA program to three technology teams including training new leaders, product owners, product managers and engineers on business and technical needs. Maximized dialy marketing calls/texts while reducing risk to Rocket Mortgage while managing TCPA program. Culture champion that fosters a fun, collaborative yet result oriented environment. Responsibilities include:

- Acting Product Manager and liaison compliance matters between technology, business and upper leadership in regards to communication compliance, ensuring safe and predictable risk for Rocket Companies
- Managed seven on-premises and cloud applications delivering flawless compliance data for Rocket Mortgage.
 Tech Stack included Angular/Angular JS UIs, Backend .Net C# Listeners and APIs, and AWS .Net (Kubernetes)
- Staffing management including quarterly and annual reviews, one-on-ones, coaching sessions, hiring and onboarding
- Daily Management of TM work including TFS/Azure DevOps (Jira equivalent), Teams and Confluence.

Technical Product Owner - **2.5 years.** Product Owner for both Data Privacy and Mortgage Servicing Analytics. Responsible for driving technology roadmap for major initiatives. Major responsibilities included being the liaison between technology, legal, upper leadership (C suite for some projects), Marketing and Banking force. Responsible for roadmaps, communication, documentation and overall product vision.

Other Positions Held at Rocket Mortgage

Technology Senior Business, Team Captain (Fannie Mae), Senior Reporting Analyst, Investor Reporting Analyst

2015 – Present - Owner/Property Manager Personal Real Estate Portfolio

Investor and manager of personal rental portfolio at peek consisting of 7 properties in metro Detroit. Currently 5 properties with over \$1 million in assets under management and \$90,000 in gross annual rent. Manages funding, acquisition and property management for entire portfolio including finding tenants, negotiating rent and maintenance of properties.







Git

Qtalk

Kevin M. Pratt

4210 Orion Rd, Rochester Hills, MI 48306 prattkev@gmail.com (248) 495-5950

2009 – 2015 Detroit Zoological Society - Enrichment Technician/ Zookeeper (NACC)

Relevant Experience

- Extensive experience in Product and Project management at a technical level in compliance applications including training and management of Product Owners and Managers
- 13+ years of professional Microsoft Office Suite with a focus on Excel/Project and other project management applications such as TFS/Azure Dev Ops
- 5+ years working in compliance related to CCPA and TCPA with sensitive data and intensive regulatory requirements
- Passion for FinTech and novel software development ideas to excite engineering staff about business needs
 - Built a mortgage simulator and personal finance simulator using Godot to help educate and excite engineering staff about the Mortgage industry (demos available upon request)
 - Built a Multiplayer Towe Defense Game designed for remote team building. Worked with staff to reinforce code best practices and improve morale while working remote during the pandemic

Technical Skills

Languages

Basic C#, C++(Arduino), Comfortable using SQL, Mongo Querying Syntax

Engineering (Software)

Power BI, Excel and Microsoft Office Suite at a technical level, .Net Console applications (Visual Studio), Source Control (Git), High level understanding of AWS software and architecture, Postman, Swagger and familiar with automated deployment pipelines (CircleCI)

Awards and Accolades

- Co-author/researcher of various zoological publications (Available Upon Request)
- QL Servicing MVP July 2018 Awarded by QL Vice President, Servicing
- August 2018 QL Technology Team Member of the Month
- Two time Rocket Mortgage Gilby/Rock Honors Nominee
- 15 "Engineered to Amaze" awards focusing on process improvement or culture contributions to Quicken Loans (now Rocket Mortgage)
- Monthly Lunch-and-Learns related to Team Member growth and career aspirations
 - Present like a Boss Simple and effective strategies to help engineers while presenting ideas to a larger audience. Applicable to all forms of communication like email, Teams messages and presentations
 - o Invest like a Boss -Basic investing terminology to arm Team Members for a strong financial future.
 - Introduction to Real Estate Investing Introduction to investing in real estate







Ω